Nate Schulz

Owner, Theoretical Media ns@theomedia.us



Background & Objective

I am a graduate of the University of Nebraska in Lincoln where I obtained a bachelor of science degree in physics with a minor in mathematics. I am in my 8th year of working with interactive media and design. I believe physics and technology are a natural pair and that my education in both the classroom and office environments offers a unique training in both fields. My desire is to work with a team of individuals who are as inspired as me to deliver cutting-edge experiences.

Experience

Owner, Theoretical Media, LLC. Lincoln, NE 2009-current

In August of 2009, I established my own small business. Theoretical Media specializes in user-experience design and implements design theory through standards-compliant web applications as well as iOS and Mac OS platforms.

Lead Front-End Web Architect, Green Vision Media. Montreal, QC 2011-2012

I worked as a consultant on GVM's elite team for 18 months developing in-house web applications built using a branch of my own JavaScript framework. The framework powers GVM's unique web experiences on desktop and mobile devices.

Lead Innovator, Nanonation, Inc. Lincoln, NE 2004-2009

My work at Nanonation evolved from design intern to a senior role in the driving the company's latest technologies that enabled rich interactive experiences in hospitality and mobile markets. I was fortunate to work directly with many of the company's partners and clients. Including several onsite meetings at Apple, Royal Caribbean, and Disney.

UI Prototyper & Pixel Painter, Pen-Link, Ltd. Lincoln, NE 2010-2011

In May of 2010, I joined Pen-Link, Ltd's new software design team where I take UI mockups and turn them in to interactive prototypes to put in front of Pen-Link, Ltd's user base. Due to the rapid nature of the prototyping phase, I created much of the interactivity using HTML5 technology.

Video Producer, Mid-America Video Lincoln, NE 2000-current

My ongoing video work for Mid-America Video is primarily videography and live editing. I also do still-photography, post-production editing, DVD production.

Education

University of Nebraska-Lincoln — BS Physics, Mathematics 2009

Strengths and Skills

I have strong leadership, communication, and presentation skills. My daily software experience includes: Adobe Creative Suite - Specializing in Photoshop, Final Cut Studio, Quartz Composer, Cinema 4D, Microsoft Office Suite. My development skill set is focused on HTML5 technology including CSS3, and object-oriented javascript used to build web applications. I also have experience with PHP5, MySQL, and Apple's iOS SDK. I am familiar java-based web application workflows and have experience maintaining JSP pages.